Robert Waller

Park Hill Phone: 07989 305 762

Ealing Email: rdwaller1984@googlemail.com

London LinkedIn: /in/robdwaller

Website: https://rbrt.wllr.info GitHub: https://github.com/RobDWaller

Skills and Knowledge

PHP, Python, JavaScript, Ubuntu, Centos, MySQL, Mongo, Laravel, Slim, WordPress, Flask, Jekyll, AWS, DigitalOcean, Tableau

Security Cleared 2015

Personal Statement

I am a software developer and manager with nearly a decade and a half of experience. Recently I spent some time with IFPI providing consultancy, advice and management support to their development team.

Prior to this I was the Head of Technology at Breakthrough Media where I ran a team of software developers, project managers and QAs. The work focused on web technologies such as WordPress, Laravel, Vue.js, and Jekyll, along with data insights work based on Tableau, Python and JavaScript. I also helped Breakthrough begin outsourcing elements of its technical work to improve cost efficiency.

Before Breakthrough Media I worked as a freelance software developer for a number of agencies. This includes BBH, Wolff Olins, WTG and WebCredible. The work ranged from private to public sector and had a focus on areas such as digital marketing and web development. Along with this I ran my own business which found success in 2012 / 13 when I released a social media analytics app that has been used by over one million people.

I have strong communication skills, have presented talks regularly in both business and public settings. And while at WebCredible I spent four years running their HTML and CSS training courses.

Experience

IFPI, Technical Consultant

August 2018 - October 2018

I worked at IFPI for a short period providing technical consultancy and advice while helping to manage the development team.

Breakthrough Media, Head of Technology

May 2016 - July 2018

Ran the software development and digital project management team. Oversaw and worked on projects ranging from small Jekyll sites, through to larger WordPress and Laravel projects. Along with data

projects based around Python, JavaScript and Tableau. Worked closely with other departments including accounts, finance and creative to ensure smooth running of projects.

WTG (Civica Group) PHP Senior Developer

October 2014 - March 2016

Worked with WTG to update one case management system and start the build of another, both in Laravel for central government departments.

Status People Ltd, Founder and Lead Developer

August 2011 - August 2018

Founder and lead developer of social media development company. Released the Fakers App in 2012 which generated one million plus users. Also produced social media marketing and analytics software for other companies.

Harkable, PHP/jQuery/Less/HTML 5 Senior Developer

September 2014

Wolff Olins, PHP/jQuery/Less Lead Developer

May 2014 - August 2014

Haygarth, PHP/jQuery Senior Developer

Feb 2014 – April 2014

Nutcase Ltd, PHP/jQuery Lead Developer

July 2012 – February 2013

Webcredible, PHP Developer and CSS Trainer

June 2012 – September 2015

Bartle Bogle Hegarty, PHP Lead Developer

October 2011 – April 2012

dbg, Support Analyst Programmer

August 2009 - August 2011

MailPerformance, Email Production Consultant

December 2007 – August 2009

Education

Lancaster University 2002-2005, BA 2:1 History

References

Adam Lewis, manager while at WTG

Hobbies & Other Information

I enjoy sport, watch a lot of football and go to the gym. I have a passion for history and philosophy so read regularly. I contribute to open source software and write blogs for dev.to. I also like whisky, TV, film and gaming.